Am I the only one that didn't know that spending too much time with our kids increases our stress
hormone? Like our bodies will quite literally punish us for it. Our cortisol goes up for
spending too much time with our kids. And the reason why is sad, but it makes sense if you
think about it, because we did not evolve to be raising them as nuclear families. Those eggs were
a lie, Steven. They had no nutrients. They wanted us to buy more houses. See, for most of history,
we did what anthropologists call alloparenting, which means everybody pitches in, right? Mom,
dad, grandparents, uncles, cousins, even neighbors sometimes. And the crazy thing is that when we
don't have this, our stress hormone goes up and so does his because it's nature's way of telling us
like you have been abandoned by your tribe. Where is your tribe? What's going on? And it also makes
him more weary of the world, right? He doesn't trust adults as much. And I didn't realize this actually
until I went on vacation with my wife's extended family. And it wasn't because we were on vacation
that it was amazing because anyone who's traveled with these things knows it could be quite stressful.
But it was because everyone pitched in, right? We were all kind of staying together. And before we
would even wake up, grandpa would be in there to pick up the baby before he even cried in the morning.
Then he passed them off to an aunt, a cousin, the great grandpa, a tia, a tío. And round and round,
he went from us to the family. And he was so happy. He started trusting everybody. I started trusting
everybody. I realized like babies are meant to truly create community. And when we don't have that,
well, our bodies pay the price for it. You know what I'm saying? We didn't evolve to be solitary
creatures. We are meant to be part of a tribe and share this beautiful gift that is children. So
when you're doing it alone and you feel stressed out, you're not broken, okay? You're doing your best.
It is what it is. And it's society that's broken, right? Be human. Anyways, that's our anthropology
lesson for the day. Happy parenting.